# **Damon Emgenbroich**

# Professional Summary

Technical professional with 22 years of large-scale enterprise software development and leadership experience in the finance and insurance industries. Highly skilled at architecting applications intended to be deployed to the cloud. Seeking to share knowledge with and mentor fellow developers. Desiring to build a world class software development organization.

### Skills

ITIL AWS SQL
DevOps Spring Boot Docker

DORA Mentoring Cloud Foundry SAFe Agile TypeScript

# Professional History

March 2018 - Present

**Software Engineering Manager** 

Liberty Mutual

- Mentors all levels of engineers in agile development methodologies such as test-driven development and inversion of control patterns which facilitate such methodologies.
- Leads cloud-based development teams in building next generation product platforms
- Facilitates IT Service Management practices across Agile Train
- Champions excellent DevOps practices for scrum teams
- Creates skill development plans for software engineers

January 2011 - March 2018

#### **Senior Software Developer**

- Led Performance Management Team
- Facilitated transition from Waterfall to Agile methodologies.
- Architected cloud based Automated Policy Corrections Tool
- Developed architectural "blueprints" to facilitate consistency across integration teams.
- Designed and developed enterprise payment request integration that tied 3<sup>rd</sup> party and internally built systems together to create a seamless robust payment request and notification framework.

#### **Notable Project**

Policy Corrections Application

- Objective: Create an application that can systematically correct policies in SOR to prevent manual rework at the agency level
- Solution: Architected cloud-based application which allows a business analyst to upload
  a list of policies needing a correction and apply a fix with minimal supervision. Came
  along side and mentored a team of technical development employees to build the Spring
  Boot application.
- Results: The application has been used to correct over 15,000 policies in SOR in 2017.
   Each automated correction saves around 8 minutes of an employee's time.

February 2007 – December 2010

ITT Educational Services Inc.

## **Senior Developer**

- Wrote architectural and coding standards for .Net, J2EE, and PL/SQL platforms
- Designed SDLC that utilized Subversion, Jira, and MediaWiki to aid in SOX compliance

#### **Notable Project**

Electronic Funds Transfer System

- Objective: Enable the business to perform electronic transactions with multiple outside business partners
- Solution: Create a Spring based web application deployed in a clustered WebSphere application server environment that would take EFT data through web services or flat files and integrate asynchronously with existing financial applications.
- Results: Reduced manual processing by 70%. Added process reporting and tracking which allows business to decrease turnaround time to receive outstanding funds.

March 2005 – February 2007

Clayton

#### **Solutions Architect**

- Assisted management team with evaluating 3rd party vendor application packages
- Conceptualized performance enhancements and implemented within platform
- Managed the transition of the platform from Clayton to client
- Handled support for outstanding platform opportunities

January 2004 – March 2005

Nisys

## Software Engineer

- Developed platform using Enterprise Java, FileNet P8, iLog Jrules, Oracle 9i and Apache Jetspeed.
- Managed development and test environment hardware

February 2000 – January 2004

Irwin Mortgage Corporation

## e-Commerce Application Developer

Developed advanced e-commerce applications

July 1999 - March 2003

#### e-Commerce Hardware Specialist

- Managed mission critical e-commerce servers.
- Handled Y2K server patching.

March 1999 - February 2000

#### **Network Support Specialist**

Provided support for all computer-related issues.

#### **Education**

January 2013 - May 2018

**Harvard Extension School**, **Harvard University**, Cambridge, Massachusetts Master of Liberal Arts in the field of Information Management Systems

September 1994 - December 1998

**Krannert School of Management, Purdue University**, West Lafayette, Indiana Bachelor of Science in Industrial Management with a Minor in Computer Science